<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0">
<channel>
<description>Independent hardcore label established in 2004.</description>
<title>Twelve Gauge Records</title>
<generator>Tumblr (3.0; @tgrex)</generator>
<link>https://blog.tgrex.com/</link>
<item>
<title>
TG045: For Your Health & Shin Guard - Death Of Spring 12″LP
</title>
<description>
<figure class="tmblr-full" data-orig-height="3609" data-orig-width="3609"><img src="https://66.media.tumblr.com/eca87679632e1b0f54e6723a9f4f9146/8c963e714f593285-43/s540x810/2a7aa41fc3177b244dbc633cb7c311fa2f41bc2d.jpg" data-orig-height="3609" data-orig-width="3609"/></figure><p>Thrilled to be working with Shin Guard again on this killer split with Columbus Ohio’s For Your Health. Both side of this split 12″LP are some of the bands’ best material to date and a sign of what’s to come.</p><p>Co-release with Middle Man, iCorrupt and Quiet Year Records, limited to 500 records on black and color vinyl. Street date: January 17, 2020.</p><p>Pre-order the record along with a Twelve Gauge exclusive shirt at <a href="https://www.tumblr.com/blog/store.tgrex.com">our webstore</a> and stream the entire record on <a href="https://www.tumblr.com/blog/music.tgrex.com">our bandcamp</a>.</p>
</description>
<link>https://blog.tgrex.com/post/188659060308</link>
<guid>https://blog.tgrex.com/post/188659060308</guid>
<pubDate>Mon, 28 Oct 2019 12:23:50 -0700</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>TG044: Frail Hands - parted/departed/apart 12″LP</title>
<description>
<figure class="tmblr-full" data-orig-height="1200" data-orig-width="1200"><img src="https://66.media.tumblr.com/92345b93b4061756752baa28a2f9a777/9c6b94c2793c6846-02/s540x810/f7d8e60551d74dbad77842acca13c7aa001a9c38.jpg" data-orig-height="1200" data-orig-width="1200"/></figure><p>Halifax, Nova Scotia’s Frail Hands is back at it again with their newest LP, parted/departed/apart. Now as a four piece, Frail Hands continue to push forward with a sound that pays homage to scream of the past. Stream “holding” now on <a href="https://music.tgrex.com/album/parted-departed-apart">our bandcamp</a>. More details about the release of the record coming soon.<br/></p>
</description>
<link>https://blog.tgrex.com/post/188571312153</link>
<guid>https://blog.tgrex.com/post/188571312153</guid>
<pubDate>Thu, 24 Oct 2019 16:29:01 -0700</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>
Out Now: Ghost Spirit - Hourglass 12″LPDon’t sleep on one of the...
</title>
<description>
<img src="https://66.media.tumblr.com/1c16a4f218a3be17c97f977197052e6a/b703eca04c9c1efa-1c/s500x750/17195884a43cf747101ff70aee6723031c10ff2a.jpg"/><br/><br/><p>Out Now: Ghost Spirit - Hourglass 12″LP</p><p>Don’t sleep on one of the best albums of the year. Ghost Spirit’s newest LP, Hourglass, pushes them into a direction and sound that is not easily described with words. You can stream the entire album on <a href="https://music.tgrex.com/album/hourglass">our bandcamp</a> and order the record and other merch on <a href="http://store.tgrex.com">our webstore</a></p>
</description>
<link>https://blog.tgrex.com/post/188571275873</link>
<guid>https://blog.tgrex.com/post/188571275873</guid>
<pubDate>Thu, 24 Oct 2019 16:26:52 -0700</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>TG042: Ghost Spirit - Hourglass 12″LP</title>
<description>
<figure data-orig-width="1500" data-orig-height="1500" class="tmblr-full"><img src="https://66.media.tumblr.com/b6c83c5755831fe7fa91df3d0a611ecd/b52ad110b3563e4c-95/s540x810/24b00039ee8819ef982148f75d310ff1da4fc0ab.jpg" alt="image" data-orig-width="1500" data-orig-height="1500" data-media-key="b6c83c5755831fe7fa91df3d0a611ecd:b52ad110b3563e4c-95"/></figure><p>Fresh off their west coast tour with The Fall of Troy, Los Angeles DIY screamo outfit Ghost Spirit returns with their new LP Hourglass on Twelve Gauge and Blue Swan Records on October 18, 2019.</p><p>Reteaming with grammy nominated producer Jack Shirley, the 8-track record leads with the blistering dissonant breakdowns of A Riddle, No Answer, then pulls you through a descent of heartfelt and urgent hardcore compositions. New member and scene veteran Nikolas Soelter (Calculator, Never Young) joins Niko Zaglaras (Lord Snow, Raw Nerve) on second guitar to bring an even more focused harsh sonic aesthetic than found on their previous self-titled LP as well as their split with Nova Scotia’s Frail Hands. On the record’s climax Look To The Stars, Taylor Jewell’s (Nuvoluscara, Elle) kinetic and signature crushing drums along with Alex Bigman’s (Seeing Means More, Fight Fair) desperate screaming showcases the band’s roots with influences including Portraits of Past, Envy, and 7 Angels 7 Plagues. In a line of consistently intense releases, Ghost Spirit’s third LP solidifies their place in the community and puts the band in league with contemporaries Portrayal of Guilt, Loma Prieta, and Touche Amore.</p><p>Listen to a single off the record at the <a href="https://t.umblr.com/redirect?z=https%3A%2F%2Fmusic.tgrex.com%2Falbum%2Fhourglass&amp;t=NDRjODUwN2ZjYTczNTAwODFkNmI2ZDBhZWRkZjg0ZDk2YTY1OTA5MiwxYjE4YWY0OTU2ZGEwYTUwOTIyMzMwNjEzMmRlMzVjNWMwNmMwZjUy">Twelve Gauge bandcamp</a>.</p><p>See the <a href="https://t.umblr.com/redirect?z=https%3A%2F%2Fdeathwishinc.com%2Fcollections%2Ftwelve-gauge&amp;t=MDU0MTAwOWRkZTY4MGI4ZGYyZTg4NWQxNjAxZjEzZGVlMGNjMzc1MSw5YjY1NjUwN2ZmYjE0Mjk0MmI3M2UyZDNmMDg1MWJmNzAyZTVlYzVl">Twelve Gauge Records online store</a> to pre-order the record and an exclusive shirt design.</p>
</description>
<link>https://blog.tgrex.com/post/187052128233</link>
<guid>https://blog.tgrex.com/post/187052128233</guid>
<pubDate>Fri, 16 Aug 2019 08:12:00 -0700</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>
Pre-orders for Shin Guard’s ‘2020′ 12″LP are up now on our...
</title>
<description>
<img src="https://66.media.tumblr.com/2971571ace6f2028aa830cd0af1509bc/tumblr_puwvqaiBXr1qav5zno1_500.jpg"/><br/><br/><p>Pre-orders for Shin Guard’s ‘2020′ 12″LP are up now on our online store: <a href="http://store.tgrex.com">http://store.tgrex.com</a>. Exclusive shirt design by Sean Leary, and the bone colored vinyl is exclusive to Twelve Gauge and limited to 100. Don’t sleep on this incredible band.</p>
</description>
<link>https://blog.tgrex.com/post/186409435438</link>
<guid>https://blog.tgrex.com/post/186409435438</guid>
<pubDate>Fri, 19 Jul 2019 15:56:34 -0700</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>TG041: Shin Guard - 2020 12″LP</title>
<description>
<figure data-orig-width="1500" data-orig-height="1500" class="tmblr-full"><img src="https://66.media.tumblr.com/726e16704d6fa8d71aac7c17fcd3ad3f/735fe48c548ed4fb-58/s540x810/3f7fa0859045f132260f07cfaf1a51ced04472d6.jpg" alt="image" data-orig-width="1500" data-orig-height="1500"/></figure><p><b>Dog Knights</b> and <b>Twelve Gauge</b> are teaming up to bring you the first time vinyl pressing of <b>Shin Guard’s ‘2020’ 12”LP</b>.<b><br/></b></p><p>Shin Guard’s ‘2020’ is a side of the Pittsburgh four piece we hadn’t quite seen before. The release takes you on a journey filled with raw emotion, angst, and melody and leaves you wondering how a band blended such a wide range of influences so perfectly. 2020 is a socially conscious hardcore album, an amalgamation of riffs and screams at peak desperation. In 26 minutes, Shin Guard covers topics such as accountability, oppression, love, and more. Sound-wise, Shin Guard is a band from screamo and hardcore fans a like &ndash; sometimes compared to The Fall Of Troy but are really drawing and blending influences from much more.</p><p>Originally recorded during the months of December 2018 to January 2019 at Cafe Verona and released in February 2019 on tape by Flowerpot.</p><p>Pre-orders will be available from both labels, each with their own exclusive vinyl color and shirt design. The LP will be officially <b>out on August 30, 2019</b>.</p><p>Listen to the full record at Shin Guard’s Bandcamp <a href="https://shinguard.bandcamp.com/album/2020">here</a>.</p><p>Pressing info:<br/>- 100 Transparent Red (Dog Knights Exclusive)<br/>- 100 Cream (Twelve Gauge Exclusive)<br/>- 300 Black</p>
</description>
<link>https://blog.tgrex.com/post/186235094658</link>
<guid>https://blog.tgrex.com/post/186235094658</guid>
<pubDate>Fri, 12 Jul 2019 07:22:48 -0700</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>Out Now: Frail Hands - Self-titled 12″LP</title>
<description>
<p>Today is the day! Frail Hands’ debut Self-titled 12″LP is available physically through our Deathwish Inc store and through all digital outlets (Spotify, Apple, Google Music, etc&hellip;).</p><figure class="tmblr-full" data-orig-height="1500" data-orig-width="1500"><img src="https://66.media.tumblr.com/a5a0283fe9676d414f4b76adca29317d/tumblr_inline_pl62aqxGWq1qap3eh_540.jpg" data-orig-height="1500" data-orig-width="1500"/></figure><p>Originally released on tape in 2017 by Middle Man Records, this is Frail Hands’ first piece of recorded music, ten tracks of raw angry screamo influenced by bands like Portraits of Past, Loma Prieta, Orchid, and La Quiete. If you liked the split with Ghost Spirit we recently released, you’ll definitely want to check this out. It’s not something to sleep on.</p><p>Recorded at the Echo Chamber by Palmer Jamieson. Mixed and mastered by Jack Shirley at the Atomic Garden.</p><p>Check out our exclusive merch and pick up a copy over at our <a href="http://store.tgrex.com">Deathwish Inc Store</a>. And if you haven’t already, stream the entire record over at our Bandcamp: <a href="http://music.tgrex.com">http://music.tgrex.com</a></p>
</description>
<link>https://blog.tgrex.com/post/181922252223</link>
<guid>https://blog.tgrex.com/post/181922252223</guid>
<pubDate>Fri, 11 Jan 2019 04:21:33 -0800</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>TG040: Frail Hands - Self-titled 12″LP and more!</title>
<description>
<p>Couple of updates for you including our newest release, the vinyl pressing of Frail Hands’ debut LP.</p><figure data-orig-width="1500" data-orig-height="1500" class="tmblr-full"><img src="https://66.media.tumblr.com/a5a0283fe9676d414f4b76adca29317d/tumblr_inline_pjqg5mEY4n1qap3eh_540.jpg" alt="image" data-orig-width="1500" data-orig-height="1500"/></figure><p><b>1) TG040: Frail Hands - Frail Hands 12″LP/Digital<br/></b>Originally released on tape in 2017 by Middle Man Records, this is Frail Hands&rsquo; first piece of recorded music, ten tracks of raw angry screamo influenced by bands like Portraits of Past, Loma Prieta, Orchid, and La Quiete. If you liked the split with Ghost Spirit we recently released, you’ll definitely want to check this out. It’s not something to sleep on.</p><p>Recorded at the Echo Chamber by Palmer Jamieson. Mixed and mastered by Jack Shirley at the Atomic Garden.</p><p><b>Out January 11, 2019</b> both physically and digitally (on all the usual outlets).</p><p><b>Stream</b> the entire record at <a href="http://music.tgrex.com/">http://music.tgrex.com</a><br/>And you can <b>pre-order</b> the record along with an exclusive long-sleeve design by Aught/Void at <a href="http://store.tgrex.com/">http://store.tgrex.com</a></p><figure data-orig-width="1200" data-orig-height="1200" class="tmblr-full"><img src="https://66.media.tumblr.com/3bc4702522a2dadaa708e1c80a5fdbe6/tumblr_inline_pjqg65IPSi1qap3eh_540.jpg" alt="image" data-orig-width="1200" data-orig-height="1200"/></figure><p><b>2) New Shirt!</b><br/>And while we have your attention, we also printed up some Twelve Gauge shirts designed by a good friend and old time supporter of the label, Adam Defiglio. They’re technically listed as pre-orders but the shirts have been printed and are on the way to Deathwish.<br/></p><figure data-orig-width="1200" data-orig-height="1200" class="tmblr-full"><img src="https://66.media.tumblr.com/1bb861d0af69aa5afe242f53b27efbf8/tumblr_inline_pjqg6e0Lpt1qap3eh_540.jpg" alt="image" data-orig-width="1200" data-orig-height="1200"/></figure><p>Thanks for your continued support.</p>
</description>
<link>https://blog.tgrex.com/post/181112249353</link>
<guid>https://blog.tgrex.com/post/181112249353</guid>
<pubDate>Fri, 14 Dec 2018 09:26:51 -0800</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>Stream Entire Split @ Noisey</title>
<description>
<p>Noisey has some nice words to say about the upcoming Ghost Spirit/Frail Hands Split as well as the full stream! Listen to the record in its entirety, the real way to enjoy it.</p><p><a href="https://noisey.vice.com/en_us/article/d3ekqy/ghost-spirit-frail-hands-split">Click here</a> to check it out. <br/>Pre-orders ship out soon, available with <a href="http://store.tgrex.com">exclusive merch here</a>.</p>
</description>
<link>https://blog.tgrex.com/post/176991558198</link>
<guid>https://blog.tgrex.com/post/176991558198</guid>
<pubDate>Tue, 14 Aug 2018 09:26:01 -0700</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>
Two More Songs ReleasedOur friend Dave at Open Mind / Saturated Brain just released two more songs...
</title>
<description>
<h1>Two More Songs Released</h1><figure class="tmblr-full" data-orig-height="1080" data-orig-width="1080"><img src="https://66.media.tumblr.com/9f338b1a7b985cbd81691c824aca0d67/tumblr_pd5iegFBT81qap3eh_540.jpg" data-orig-height="1080" data-orig-width="1080"/></figure><p>Our friend Dave at Open Mind / Saturated Brain just released two more songs off the upcoming Ghost Spirit/Frail Hands Split. <a href="http://openmindsaturatedbrain.blogspot.com/2018/08/ghost-spirit-frail-hands-exclusive.html">Click here</a> to listen!</p><p>And remember, album is released in just a few more weeks on August 24. Pre-order the LP and exclusive merch <a href="https://deathwishinc.com/collections/twelve-gauge">here</a>.</p><p>Thanks for listening!</p>
</description>
<link>https://blog.tgrex.com/post/176773676008</link>
<guid>https://blog.tgrex.com/post/176773676008</guid>
<pubDate>Wed, 08 Aug 2018 09:42:18 -0700</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>TG039: Ghost Spirit/Frail Hands Split</title>
<description>
<figure data-orig-width="300" data-orig-height="300" class="tmblr-full"><img src="https://66.media.tumblr.com/004da0d939f8951a0e14b8f624044306/tumblr_inline_pbsv9qA4vq1qap3eh_400.jpg" alt="image" data-orig-width="300" data-orig-height="300"/></figure><p>I’m thrilled to announce the details for TG039, the latest Twelve Gauge release:</p><p>DIY screamo outfits GHOST SPIRIT and FRAIL HANDS have teamed up to bring you a full-length split 12” LP co-released on TWELVE GAUGE RECORDS and BLUE SWAN RECORDS.</p><p>Hailing from Los Angeles, Ghost Spirit is a four piece made up from members of Lord Snow, Letters to Catalonia, and Seeing Means More. Their side of the split comes as a follow-up to their unrelenting debut self-titled LP, released on Blue Swan Records in the spring of 2017. Produced by Jack Shirley (Deafheaven, Loma Prieta, Oathbreaker), these 6 new songs expand on their traditional screamo sound and into the more abrasive and melodic side of hardcore. </p><p>From across the continent, Frail Hands is a five piece from Halifax, Nova Scotia with members of King&rsquo;s Girls and Heisse. This is the follow up to their widely received self-titled debut LP released on Middle Man Records in the fall of 2017. Mixed and mastered by Jack Shirley, the energy of these 6 songs hit you in the face with a sonic assault of pure emotion that leaves you in a state of trance. </p><p>These two bands are very well suited for each other and bring their own variation of real screamo thats pays homage to bands like Portraits of Past, Loma Prieta, Orchid, and La Quiete. If you want to temporarily forget you’re living in 2018 and be taken back to a time when music was raw, heartfelt, and emotional&hellip;this record is for you.</p><p>This split 12” LP will be available in stores and online on August 24, 2018.</p><p><b>Listen</b> to a track from each band at <a href="http://www.noecho.net/features/ghost-spirit-frail-hands-split">NoEcho.net</a>.</p><p><b>Pre-order</b> the record and merch at the <a href="https://deathwishinc.com/collections/twelve-gauge?sort_by=created-descending">Twelve Gauge Records online store</a>.</p>
</description>
<link>https://blog.tgrex.com/post/175851120498</link>
<guid>https://blog.tgrex.com/post/175851120498</guid>
<pubDate>Fri, 13 Jul 2018 09:05:31 -0700</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>Record Store Day 2018</title>
<description>
<p>*Mic check* After a lot of radio silence, I’m back at it. Two things I wanted to make you aware of:</p><figure data-orig-width="1200" data-orig-height="1200" class="tmblr-full"><img src="https://66.media.tumblr.com/4c60af81408bb88f1d3ddbe80305e0f7/tumblr_inline_p7g305hs4y1qap3eh_540.jpg" alt="image" data-orig-width="1200" data-orig-height="1200"/></figure><p>1) We’ll be participating in Deathwish Inc’s annual Record Store Day sale. This year’s RSD sale starts Friday at 12am EST and ends Sunday at 12am EST. All our merch and records are at 20% off, not to mention all of theirs! Be sure to take a look. Link: <a href="http://dthw.sh/twelvegauge">http://dthw.sh/twelvegauge</a></p><p>2) I’m working with two awesome bands on a great split 12″LP that we’ll announce in the coming few weeks. Stay tuned&hellip;</p><p>Thanks,<br/>Jihad</p>
</description>
<link>https://blog.tgrex.com/post/173101354778</link>
<guid>https://blog.tgrex.com/post/173101354778</guid>
<pubDate>Thu, 19 Apr 2018 11:22:17 -0700</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>Record Store Day 2016</title>
<description>
<figure data-orig-width="1552" data-orig-height="1552" class="tmblr-full"><img src="https://66.media.tumblr.com/78fc3812902137cc45facc31032bda99/tumblr_inline_o5mtv38Bjv1qap3eh_540.jpg" alt="image" data-orig-width="1552" data-orig-height="1552"/></figure><p>As part of RSD 2016, starting tonight at midnight (Friday April 15) we’re offering <b>21% off all items</b> on our Deathwish Inc store, including merchandise! Use code <b>RSD2016</b> at <a href="http://store.tgrex.com">http://store.tgrex.com</a> to take advantage of this. Sale ends this Sunday April 17.</p><p>Thanks for your continued support.</p>
</description>
<link>https://blog.tgrex.com/post/142798136863</link>
<guid>https://blog.tgrex.com/post/142798136863</guid>
<pubDate>Thu, 14 Apr 2016 09:34:16 -0700</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>20% Off At Our New Online Store</title>
<description>
<p>The fine folks at Deathwish Inc are now exclusively distributing our releases and hosting our online store. We’ve kicked this new store off with a 20% off your entire order code TWELVEGAUGE20.</p><p><a href="http://store.deathwishinc.com/category/TWELVEGAUGE.html">Check out the new store here</a>.</p><p>Moving across the country this month and will get to work as soon as I can. Thanks for all your support.</p>
</description>
<link>https://blog.tgrex.com/post/140697414508</link>
<guid>https://blog.tgrex.com/post/140697414508</guid>
<pubDate>Tue, 08 Mar 2016 10:34:58 -0800</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>Online Store Update</title>
<description>
<figure class="tmblr-full" data-orig-height="1714" data-orig-width="1996"><img src="https://66.media.tumblr.com/f188b89d2d9b1b4d71015e1b8bacef62/tumblr_inline_o23d9enetC1qap3eh_540.png" data-orig-height="1714" data-orig-width="1996"/></figure><p>We’re in the process of shipping all our merch to our friends at Deathwish Inc who’ll now also beginning selling our apparel in addition to music.</p><p>We’ve shut down our Shopify store so please visit <a href="http://go.tgrex.com/store">our new store for vinyl and digital music</a> with merch on the way in the coming few weeks.</p>
</description>
<link>https://blog.tgrex.com/post/138746760218</link>
<guid>https://blog.tgrex.com/post/138746760218</guid>
<pubDate>Fri, 05 Feb 2016 12:36:58 -0800</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>Free Music. No, seriously.</title>
<description>
<p>Hi all,<br/>Starting today, our entire discography is available for free on our <a href="http://music.tgrex.com">Bandcamp digital music store</a>. You’re welcome to leave a few bucks, but we don’t expect it. Enjoy! And in the words of Sabertooth Zombie: play loud.</p><p>Love,<br/>TG</p>
</description>
<link>https://blog.tgrex.com/post/137793475563</link>
<guid>https://blog.tgrex.com/post/137793475563</guid>
<pubDate>Thu, 21 Jan 2016 20:35:08 -0800</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>Massive Moving Sale</title>
<description>
<figure data-orig-width="500" data-orig-height="371" class="tmblr-full"><img src="https://66.media.tumblr.com/cd3cebfae1acfa8c3af1be1a4e58cd54/tumblr_inline_o17zkwfhia1qap3eh_540.jpg" data-orig-width="500" data-orig-height="371"/></figure><p><br/>In the coming few months I’ll be moving across the States to NYC and as a result will be transitioning my online store to Deathwish, my distributor. It’s a lot of money and trouble moving things across the country, so I’m having a one-time giant sale with ridiculous sale prices.</p><p>All t-shirts are between $4-6<br/>12″s for $6<br/>7″s for 3</p><p>And some bundle deals:<br/>- 4 12″s of our choice (leave us notes and we’ll do our best) for $20<br/>- 4 7″s for $10<br/>- 3 shirts for $12</p><p><a href="http://store.tgrex.com/">This sale here until the end of the month</a>. Please note that if you order only vinyl, we can refund the difference in shipping for Media Mail. Just leave a note, no problem :)</p><p>Thanks for your support. Can’t wait to settle into NYC and get back to business. Stay tuned for more updates.</p>
</description>
<link>https://blog.tgrex.com/post/137643404333</link>
<guid>https://blog.tgrex.com/post/137643404333</guid>
<pubDate>Tue, 19 Jan 2016 13:56:00 -0800</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>Holiday Sale</title>
<description>
<p>As a thanks for your continued support please use code TGHOLIDAY for 40% off your entire order on <a href="http://store.tgrex.com">our online store</a>. Have a great holiday season.</p>
</description>
<link>https://blog.tgrex.com/post/134239347858</link>
<guid>https://blog.tgrex.com/post/134239347858</guid>
<pubDate>Sun, 29 Nov 2015 18:43:29 -0800</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>Out Now: Nervous - Duration and Delusion</title>
<description>
<figure class="tmblr-full" data-orig-height="1600" data-orig-width="1600"><img src="https://66.media.tumblr.com/a4674f4efce560f482ab4598539f7bc7/tumblr_inline_nworll630u1qap3eh_540.jpg" data-orig-height="1600" data-orig-width="1600"/></figure><p><i>Duration and Delusion, </i>the second EP by Oakland trio <b><a href="http://facebook.com/nervoussongs">Nervous,</a></b> is out today on <b><a href="http://tgrex.com/">Twelve Gauge Records</a></b> and the band&rsquo;s own <b>Turbulent Records.</b><br/><br/>Stream <i>Duration and Delusion</i>, <b><a href="http://www.cvltnation.com/cvlt-nation-premiere-streaming-nervous-duration-and-delusion-review/">here</a>, </b>and buy <b><a href="http://store.tgrex.com">here</a>. For a limited time get both the self-titled 12″LP and the new 12″EP for $14.</b><br/><br/>&ldquo;Fucking stupendous,&rdquo; &ldquo;wrathful, angular,&rdquo; and &ldquo;a crusher&rdquo; are just some of the words being slapped on this outstanding new record. Clean, warm guitar tones and minimal drums bash out totally epic jams &ndash; more musical than what we think of as punk, more stripped-down than what we think of as noise-rock. Nervous slays with simplicity and with the secret weapon that is frontman Jake Spek&rsquo;s voice. Spek welcomes us into his unhinged world with vocals that gush realness, a range of low mutterings and horrified freakouts, recalling elder maniacs <b>Black Francis</b> and <b>David Yow.</b> He says <i>Duration and Delusion </i>is a meditation on the concept of time and its role in our society.<br/><br/><i>Duration and Delusion</i> follows Nervous&rsquo; 2013 self-titled debut EP. Watch the excellent &ldquo;Good Morning&rdquo; video off that EP, <a href="http://noisey.vice.com/blog/watch-nervous-video-for-good-morning"><b>here.</b></a><br/><br/><i>&ldquo;Noisy hardcore&hellip; channeling </i>My War<i>-era Black Flag.&rdquo;</i><br/><i><b>–BrooklynVegan</b></i><br/><i><b><br/></b></i><i>&ldquo;</i>Duration and Delusion<i> is fucking stupendous. A firework of quaking rage&hellip;&rdquo;</i><br/><i><b>–CVLT Nation</b></i><br/><i><br/>&ldquo;Anxiety isn&rsquo;t cool, but appropriately named Oakland hardcore punk trio Nervous totally are.&rdquo;<br/><b>–Decibel</b></i><br/><i><br/></i><i>&ldquo;Wrathful, angular punk in the mold of early-90s noizemongers Jesus Lizard, the almighty Nirvana, etc.&rdquo; </i><br/><i><b>–High Times</b></i><br/><i><b><br/></b></i><i>&ldquo;It is a crusher. You don&rsquo;t hear band absolutely crush great punk these days, but Nervous do it and do it well.&rdquo;</i><br/><i><b>–American Aftermath</b></i><br/></p>
</description>
<link>https://blog.tgrex.com/post/131760381598</link>
<guid>https://blog.tgrex.com/post/131760381598</guid>
<pubDate>Fri, 23 Oct 2015 11:34:35 -0700</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>Nervous “Duration And Delusion”</title>
<description>
<figure class="tmblr-full" data-orig-height="1600" data-orig-width="1600"><img src="https://66.media.tumblr.com/a4674f4efce560f482ab4598539f7bc7/tumblr_inline_nv97u4hRkw1qap3eh_540.jpg" data-orig-height="1600" data-orig-width="1600"/></figure><p>Oakland, California trio <b><a href="http://facebook.com/nervoussongs">Nervous</a></b> announces new EP <i><b>Duration and Delusion,</b> </i>coming <b>October 23rd</b> on <b><a href="http://tgrex.com/">Twelve Gauge Records</a></b> and <b>Turbulent Records.</b><br/><br/>Of Nervous&rsquo; 2013 self-titled debut album, <b>High Times</b> wrote: <i>&ldquo;Wrathful, angular punk in the mold of early-90s noizemongers Jesus Lizard, the almighty Nirvana, etc.&rdquo; </i><br/><b><br/></b><b>Terrorizer</b> called it <i>&ldquo;paranoid punk rock, not unlike The Jesus Lizard covering &lsquo;My War&rsquo; era Black Flag.&rdquo;</i><br/><i><br/></i>New EP <i>Duration and Delusion</i> follows up the debut with more of what made that album great: minimal noise-punk jams seethe with feeling, existing in a space right between the raging and desperate and the totally stoned. <br/><br/>Frontman Jake Spek&rsquo;s anxiety-ridden rasp is the voice of a man carrying the weight of the world and trying to make sense of it all. Clean guitars strum urgently and break into surf rock tones as bare-bones drums and bass pound out tight <b>Crass</b>-like cadences. The band – Spek, drummer Jacob Harris, and bassist Conrad Nichols – name influences like <b>The Melvins, Born Against, </b>and the entire rosters of <b>Ebullition</b> and <b>Dischord Records.</b> <br/><br/>Spek says <i>Duration and Delusion</i> is a record about time: &ldquo;It&rsquo;s about our understanding of time and how it controls us. How our understanding of it shapes how we approach everything. Time as a power structure and a tool used in the reproduction of capital. The limitations imposed by structures we ourselves have created and abide by. The police. The state. Capitalism. People taking the streets. And weed, of course. Kill the cop in your head.&rdquo;<br/><br/>&ldquo;The Break,&rdquo; one such song about the march of time, opens with these lines: <i>&ldquo;I face the wave / Tremble at its feet / It swallows me whole / And sand&rsquo;s stuck to me / I&rsquo;m feeling tense / And the sand&rsquo;s stuck to me / Take off my clothes / It&rsquo;s still stuck to me.&rdquo; </i><br/><br/>Stream &ldquo;The Break,&rdquo; via <b>Decibel,</b> <a href="http://decibelmagazine.com/blog/2015/8/26/oakland-punks-nervous-give-you-the-break"><b>here.</b></a><br/><br/><i>Duration and Delusion</i> was recorded and mixed by <b>Max Senna (Ash Borer, Wild Moth) </b>and mastered by <b>Alan Douches (Torche, Young Widows).</b><br/><br/>The tracklist is as follows:<br/><br/>1) The Future <br/>2) Lapse<br/>3) Breathing and Choking<br/>4) The Break<br/>5) Yearly<br/>6) Nostalgia and Expiration<br/><br/>Central figures in the Bay Area&rsquo;s DIY hardcore punk scene, the members of Nervous run Oakland DIY space <b>The Hive.</b>Turbulent Records is Spek&rsquo;s own new label – <i>Duration and Delusion,</i> a co-release with San Francisco&rsquo;s superb Twelve Gauge Records (Power, Sabertooth Zombie, Youth Funeral), is Turbulent&rsquo;s first release.<br/></p><figure class="tmblr-full" data-orig-height="1066" data-orig-width="1600"><img src="https://66.media.tumblr.com/cfa3657462a2ce72412501dd75cf5390/tumblr_inline_nv97v4EsZa1qap3eh_540.jpg" data-orig-height="1066" data-orig-width="1600"/></figure>
</description>
<link>https://blog.tgrex.com/post/129873524028</link>
<guid>https://blog.tgrex.com/post/129873524028</guid>
<pubDate>Fri, 25 Sep 2015 15:30:55 -0700</pubDate>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>